<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog Posts - Non-Tech on Aashish Koirala</title><link>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/nontech/</link><description>Recent content in Blog Posts - Non-Tech on Aashish Koirala</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/nontech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Oatmeal, it's what's for breakfast!</title><link>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/nontech/oatmeal-its-whats-for-breakfast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/nontech/oatmeal-its-whats-for-breakfast/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I am in my healthy and fit zone, I get a lot done. It is quite clear there is no big secret to keeping fit - you exercise and you eat well. To that end, few would disagree that oatmeal is as healthy as they come when it comes to breakfast foods. Few would also disagree that making rolled oats is not a fun activity and eating rolled oats even less so. After about a year and a half of trial and error, I have settled on an oatmeal recipe that is easy and fast to make, decent enough to eat, and a good balance of nutrients. Most importantly, it fills you up and sets your body on the right track for the day - which is what a good breakfast should do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Where the Crow Came to Die</title><link>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/nontech/where-the-crow-came-to-die/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/nontech/where-the-crow-came-to-die/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was running as fast as I could, but the yak kept gaining on me. All of a sudden, I found myself in my lodge room. I jumped on the bed, only to discover to my horror that the yak had made it to the room as well. With all its fury, the yak jumped on me. That is when I woke up from the vivid nightmare with cold sweat all over my body. Perfectly horizontal on the bed, my head felt fine. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put a finger on it, but I knew that there was something that was not right with my body. I decided to get up for a quick trip to the latrine. As soon as I left the bed, the entire room started spinning around me. I could hardly stand or walk straight. That is when the troubling night began.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>