<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bootstrap on Aashish Koirala</title><link>https://aashishkoirala.com/tags/bootstrap/</link><description>Recent content in Bootstrap on Aashish Koirala</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aashishkoirala.com/tags/bootstrap/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using CSS Media Queries for Responsive UI Design</title><link>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/using-css-media-queries-for-responsive-ui-design/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/using-css-media-queries-for-responsive-ui-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using something like &lt;a href="http://getbootstrap.com/">Bootstrap&lt;/a> for a &lt;a href="https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/dancing-with-responsive-design/">responsive UI&lt;/a> covers most of the bases. But if you need more control, it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to get familiar with &lt;a href="http://www.w3schools.com/css/css_rwd_mediaqueries.asp">Media Queries&lt;/a> in CSS. It might come in handy some time, plus that is what Bootstrap uses under the hood as well, and it never hurts to learn how the tools you use work. The &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/CSS/Media_Queries/Using_media_queries">Mozilla page&lt;/a> on media queries goes into just the right amount of detail and gives you a good outline of everything you can do with it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bootstrap Modal With AngularJS</title><link>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/bootstrap-modal-with-angularjs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/bootstrap-modal-with-angularjs/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;ll look at a relatively low hanging fruit in case you&amp;rsquo;re working with vanilla AngularJS and Twitter Bootstrap and are not relying on other add-ons such as AngularUI&amp;rsquo;s Bootstrap extension. One common need I have is to be able to show or hide Bootstrap modals based on a property on my view-model. Here&amp;rsquo;s a simplified view of the controller:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>var app = angular.module('app', ...);
...

app.controller('ctrl', function ($scope, ...) {
	...
	$scope.showModal = false;
	...
});
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>And here is the HTML:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dancing with Responsive Design</title><link>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/dancing-with-responsive-design/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/dancing-with-responsive-design/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have been hearing about &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Responsive_web_design">responsive design&lt;/a> on and off for some time now, and it has always appealed to me as a pattern to follow for web-based user interfaces. CSS3 is obviously quite powerful and media queries provide a relatively easy way to build one unified UI that looks great on PCs, but then adapts and shape-shifts accordingly when viewed on a smartphone or tablet without having to completely re-implement a &amp;ldquo;mobile site&amp;rdquo; as so many do today. Since UI design is not my core area, though, I never could quite gather the energy to do something with it. Then I saw support for responsiveness in the new &lt;a href="http://getbootstrap.com/css/#responsive-utilities">Bootstrap 3&lt;/a>. Like with all other aspects of web UI design, it makes responsiveness that much easier as well. As added motivation, I tried out my &lt;a href="https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/yes-one-more-to-do-application/">To Do&lt;/a> application in my smartphone - and it looked awful.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TypeScript, AngularJS and Bootstrap- The Killer Combo</title><link>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/typescript-angularjs-and-bootstrap-the-killer-combo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aashishkoirala.com/blog/tech/typescript-angularjs-and-bootstrap-the-killer-combo/</guid><description>&lt;p>After having recently used this combination, I am in love with it. For those unfamiliar with any of these, here are quick one liners:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://typescript.codeplex.com/">TypeScript&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> is a JavaScript superset from &lt;strong>Microsoft&lt;/strong> that compiles down to JavaScript and adds static typing and other neat features like classes and what not. It is worth mentioning that none other than &lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anders_Hejlsberg">Anders Hejlsberg&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> (the father of C#) was involved in its development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="http://angularjs.org/">AngularJS&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> is a JavaScript framework geared towards building rich and testable single-page applications. This one comes from none other than &lt;strong>Google&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>